Guide to the Andrew Jackson Faulk Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Andrew Jackson Faulk papers
1817-1896
WA MSS 195
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.88
(5 boxes)
The collection deals mainly with Andrew Faulk's official duties in Dakota Territory as governor and superintendent of Indian Affairs, and as clerk of the United States District Court. There are also family papers spanning most of his life.
Faulk, Andrew Jackson, 1814-1898
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of William Robertson Coe.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
ANDREW JACKSON FAULK (1814-1898)
Andrew Jackson Faulk was born at Milford, Pike County, Pennsylvania, on November 26, 1814. In 1815, his parents moved to Kittanning, in Armstrong County, where Faulk was educated. He later learned the printing trade, studied law, and took an active part in local politics. In 1861, President Abraham Lincoln appointed him post-trader to the Yankton Indian Agency in the Dakota Territory. In 1864, he returned to Pennsylvania and engaged in the oil business until 1866 when President Andrew Johnson appointed him governor of Dakota. He served in that office until 1869, when President Ulysses S. Grant appointed John A. Burbank to succeed him. Faulk continued to live in Yankton until his death, and was active in local politics and in the opening and development of the Black Hills. He served as an advisor to the peace commission under General Sherman which concluded the treaty of Fort Laramie in 1868. He was appointed clerk of the U.S. District Court, Second Judicial District, in November 1873, and served until 1881.
Scope and Contents
The manuscripts in the Andrew Jackson Faulk Papers deal mainly with Faulk's official duties as governor and superintendent of Indian affairs in Dakota Territory and as clerk of the U.S. District Court. Correspondence with Faulk and Faulk's correspondence with his wife and family are, in general, represented by original letters. Faulk's letters to others are usually signed copies made for his official files. In addition to the letters and documents listed below, the manuscripts include Faulk's commissions as justice of the peace in Armstrong Co., Pennsylvania, and as lieutenant colonel in the Pennsylvania Militia, as well as deeds, indentures, leases for property in Pennsylvania and in Dakota, accounts current of the Superintendent of Indian Affairs with the Commissioners N. G. Taylor, Charles E. Mix, L. V. Bogy, and Ely S. Parker, including vouchers, abstracts, receipts, property returns, reports on employees (1866-1869), and correspondence with the Commissioner and auditors in the Treasury Department (1866-75). Also found in the collection are accounts current of the executive department of the Territory, emolument returns (1875-81), receipts (1873-81), correspondence with the Solicitor of the Treasury and U.S. Comptroller, decisions and reports of cases, accounts of the clerk of the U.S. District Court, and personal memoranda, notes, bills and receipts and twenty-five photographs of friends and Indians. There are around 2,000 pages in the collection.
The following detailed list of papers in the collection can also be found on pp. 94-104 of A Catalogue of Manuscripts in the Collection of Western Americana in the Yale University Library, Mary C. Withington, editor.
Appendix: Alphabetical List of Correspondents
Faulk, Andrew Jackson. Eight letters to his wife. April 21, 1865- April 3, 1882. 17 pp.
---- Letter to his son, T. B. Faulk. July 2, 1877. With T. B. Faulk's answer on the same sheet, July 6, 1877. 2 pp.
---- Letter to [Dr. Avery]. June 27, 1884. Signed copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to L. H. Bailey. July 18, 1887. Signed draft. 1 p.
---- Two letters to John S. Boutwell. March 11, May 17, 1869. Signed copies. 3 pp.
---- Four letters to Britton, Gray & Drummond. June 28, 1875-March 3, 1876. Signed copies. 7 pp.
---- Two letters to O. H. Browning. October 31, 1867, February 20, 1869. Signed copies. 2 pp.
---- Two drafts of a letter to L. F. Cavalier. April 18, 1892. Signed. 9 pp.
---- Letter to Duane B. Cooley. March 15, 1871. With "Extract from evidence taken touching the ... contest of election for delegate -- Burleigh vs. Armstrong." Signed by Phil K. Faulk, April 8, 1871. Copies. 6 pp.
---- Letter to Wills De Hass. March 21, 1849. Signed copy. 4 pp.
---- Letter to H. B. Denman. January 22, 1867. Signed copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to E. W. Foster. April 26, 1892. Signed copy. 4 pp.
---- Draft of a letter to President Grant, recommending George W. Bible. March, 1869. Unsigned. 1 p.
---- Draft of a letter to President Hayes, urging the reappointment of Governor Pennington. Signed also by N. Edmunds "and some 20 others. Sent January 15, 1872." 1 p.
---- Letter to Alexander Hughes. September 25, 1877. With undated answer on the same page. 1 p.
---- Letter to H. A. Humphrey. May 26, 1884. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to William Jayne. September 12, 1862. Signed copy. 3 pp.
---- Letter to President Johnson. [May 14, 1868.] Signed copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to Captain J. L. Kelly. March 3, 1867. 3 pp.
---- Draft of a letter to D. M. Mills and others. May 16, 1868. Signed. 5 pp.
---- Letter to G. L. Ordway. March 1884. Signed copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to William H. Seward. September 24, 1866. Signed copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to Charles H. Sheldon. February 23, 1893. Signed copy. 4 pp.
---- Account books, with memoranda of arrivals and departures of friends, important events, and business records. January 5, 1863- March 1869. 3 vols. [i.e., 93 pp.] 12-17 cm. Original bindings.
---- To the sheriff of Yankton County, ordering the arrest of James D. Berger and his delivery to Charles W. W. Clark of Michigan. March 11, 1869. Signed by Faulk with the State seal affixed. Endorsed by George W. Black, sheriff, that he arrested Berger March 12, 1869 and delivered him to Clark. With a letter to Faulk from T. C. Carpenter, prosecuting attorney, St. Joseph Co., Mich., March 8, 1869, enclosing a requisition for the delivery of James D. Berger, signed by Henry P. Baldwin, Governor, P. L. Spalding, Secretary of State, February 24, 1869 [broadside. 26 x 42 cm.]; and a letter from G. C. Moody to Faulk, March 11, 1869. 4 pp.
---- "A bill to amend Chapter 14 of the Session laws of 1865-66" and "An act to create the tenth Representative district and for other purposes." Endorsed by Horace J. Austin, President, George I. Foster, Secretary, Enos Stutsman, Speaker, P. H. Halnan, Chief Clerk. With note attached: "Jan. 10, 1868. Two bills received this day and not returned for want of time to consider them properly on account of objectionable features." 4 pp.
---- Veto message to G. C. Moody, Speaker of the House of Representatives, House Bill No. 48, January 14, 1869. Endorsed: "A copy taken and sent this retained." 4 pp.
---- Message to Enos Stutsman, Speaker of the House, vetoing a bill to simplify the proceedings of the courts of the Territory. January 6, 1868. With a note at the end that the bill had been amended and the veto withdrawn, January 7, 1868. Signed copy. 6 pp.
---- Report to D. N. Cooley, Commissioner of Indian Affairs, on the condition of the Dakota superintendency. October 10, 1866. "Office copy." 9 pp.
---- Report of N. G. Taylor, Commissioner of Indian Affairs. September 9, 1867. Draft. 22 pp.
---- Remarks to One-that-Kills-the-Eagle. Endorsed: "July 8, 1868. Orig. sent with other vouchers to Washington, D.C." Copy. 4 pp. With notes of Eagle's remarks. 2 pp.
---- "Schedule of claims of Yankton Indians" with accounts and memoranda. November 1861-June 1864. 14 pp. Original binding.
---- Receipt for payments to half breeds of the Yankton Sioux tribe under the treaty of April 19, 1858. Certified as correct by A. J. Faulk. December 31, 1868. Seventy names are listed with the amounts due and signatures or marks of the recipients and witnesses. Signature only. 1 p. 55 1/2 x 82 1/2 cm.
---- Faulk, A. J. Docket of the clerk of the U.S. District Court, Second Judicial District, September 24, 1875-August 13, 1881. The books, numbered A No. 2-A No. 5, include notations of a few personal or family events not in the legal calendar. 4 vols. [i.e., 385 pp.] 17 cm. Original bindings.
---- Oath as clerk of the U.S. District Court, Second Judicial District, November 29, 1873. Renewed January 12, 1874. Witnessed by P. C. Shannon. 2 pp.
---- Oath as clerk of the District Court of Yankton County. November 23, 1873. Renewed January 12, 1874. Witnessed by P. C. Shannon. 1 p.
Albright, Richard. Letter to Mark Parmer. September 25, 1879. 4 pp.
Allen, D. K. Letter to Faulk. February 17, 1868. 2 pp.
Arcange, Walter. Patent, certificate No. 478E, for land in Vermillion. May 21, 1867. Signed for Andrew Johnson by Frank Cowan, Secretary, and J. N. Granger, recorder. Certified a true copy, February 11, 1895, by S. W. Lamoreux, Commissioner of the General Land Office, and recorded February 18, 1895, by J. P. Serr. Printed form. 1 p. 46 x 32 1/2 cm.
Armstrong, Moses Kimball. Four letters to Faulk. January 10, 1873-February 23, 1875. 7 pp.
Bailey, L. H. Two letters to Faulk. July 12, October 5, 1887. 2 pp.
Baldwin, Mrs. Mary McCook. Letter to Faulk. February 15, 1882. 3 pp.
Bayless, Lott S. Letter to Mr. and Mrs. Faulk. March 3, 1882. 2 pp.
Beadle, William Henry Harrison. Letter to Faulk. November 27, 1871. Signature only. 3 pp.
Bible, George W. Letter to Faulk. February 15, 1869. 2 pp.
Black, T. D. Letter to Faulk. November 21, 1877. 1 p.
Blakeley, William. Four letters to Faulk. October 13, 1866- April 25, 1890. 8 pp.
Blakeley & Miller. Letter to Faulk. May 6, 1868. 1 p.
Boyle, John W. Letter to Faulk. November 17, 1868. 3 pp.
Bradford, Daniel P. Letter to Faulk. March 24, 1869. 4 pp.
Bristol, William M. Letter to Faulk, transmitting a resolution of the Board of Education of Yankton. May 16, 1877. With a duplicate of the report of the case, County of Yankton vs. A. J. Faulk, signed by F. Schnauber, May 26, 1877. 6 pp.
Britton, Gray & Drummond. Six letters to Faulk. June 14, 1875- March 9, 1876. 10 pp.
Brodhead, J. J. Letter to Faulk. April 13, 1875. 2 pp.
Brodhead, J. M. Letter to Faulk. June 2, 1875. With a four-page memorandum. Signed: "per J.D.T." 5 pp.
Brodhead, John F. Two letters to Faulk. October 26, November 28, 1866. 4 pp.
Brodhead, John H. Nine letters to Faulk. October 17, 1866-June 19, 1878. 21 pp.
Brookings, Wilmot Wood. Letter to W. A. Burleigh. February 26, 1869. 2 pp.
Brown, Jason Brevoort. Three letters to Faulk. September 6-9, 1875. 3 pp.
Browning, Orville Hickman. Three letters to Faulk. October 3, 1866- April 4, 1867. Signatures only. 4 pp.
---- Letter to Charles E. Mix. November 16, 1865. Copy. 3 pp.
---- Instructions to N. G. Taylor. August 8, 1867, under the Act of July 29, 1867, to establish peace with the hostile Indians. Copy by Faulk, who accompanied the commission by invitation. 11 pp.
Bruguier, Charles, Eugene, and Joseph. Three powers of attorney to W. A. Burleigh to collect money due under the Yankton treaty of April 19, 1858. Each signed with the other two as witnesses, December 23, 1868. With affidavits by John W. Boyle and endorsed: "Received the above ... 12 March 1869. Chas B. Wing." 12 pp.
Burbank, John A. Letter to Mr. Walters. December 12, 1871. 1 p.
Burleigh, Andrew F. Seven letters to his grandfather, A. J. Faulk. December 16, 1876-October 7, 1883, 18 pp.
---- Letter to his grandmother, Mrs. Faulk. September 27 [1879]. 2 pp.
Burleigh, Caroline Faulk (Mrs. Walter A.). Letter to Faulk. [n.p., n.d.] Endorsed: "Answered October 31, 1867." 1 p.
---- Notice served on Simon Eisenman and Charles Eisenman. October 2, 1878. Endorsed: "Original Notice served by copy October 2, 1878 ... To Chas. Eisenman in his store room. A. J. Faulk." 1 p.
Burleigh, Walter A. 63 letters to Faulk. December 30, 1863- December 14, 1884. 128 pp.
---- Letter to Lewis V. Bogy. January 3, 1866. Copy. 6 pp.
Burleigh, Walter A., Jr. Letter to his grandfather, A. J. Faulk. December 20, 1882. 2 pp.
Butler, David. Letter to Governor Faulk. October 10, 1867, transmitting a copy of the resolution ratifying the amendment to the Constitution of the United States, June 15, 1867. Certified a true copy by Thomas P. Kennard, Secretary of the State of Nebraska. Printed. 3 pp.
Butt, William. Certificate that A. J. Faulk is a member of the Methodist Church at Kittanning, Armstrong Co., Pa. November 8, 1835. 1 p.
Byles, C. N. Letter to the clerk of the District Court. Montesana, W.T., February 21, 1874. 2 pp.
Callan, John F. Letter to W. A. Burleigh. February 5, 1869. 1 p.
Cameron, James Donald. Letter to Faulk. December 10, 1881. 2 pp.
Campbell, C. T. Three letters to Faulk. March 18, 1878-March 24, 1885. 3 pp.
Cary, J. E. Two letters to Faulk. August 5, 30, 1867. 4 pp.
---- Letter to F. B. Van Vleck. May 26, 1871. 3 pp.
Chandler, William Eaton. Five letters to Faulk. May 8, 1889- January 21, 1896. Two of the letters are typewritten. 5 pp.
Church, Louis Kossuth. Letter to Faulk. May 7, 1887. Typewritten. 1 p.
Clevenger, Shobal Vail. Letter to Faulk. May 14, 1874. 1 p.
Conant, Charles P. Letter to Faulk. August 11, 1874. With a copy on verso of Faulk's letter to 3d Asst. Postmaster General, August 17, 1874. 2 pp.
Conger, Patrick H. Two letters to Faulk. January 31, 1867, November 26, 1868. 2 pp.
Coningsby, Robert. Letter to Faulk, enclosing a circular explaining his purpose in coming to America, "An English Enquiry into American Manufactures and the Condition of the Working Classes." [Broadside. 25 1/2 cm.] Cooper Institute [New York], July 22, 1868. 1 p.
Cook, Charles. Letter to Faulk. April 1, 1867. 1 p.
Cook, John. Letter to Faulk. March 18, 1863. 1 p.
Cooley, Duane B. Letter to Faulk. March 15, 1871. With supporting statements signed by L. Congleton, March 15, 1871, and C. G. Irish, March 27, 1871. 4 pp.
Copley, Josiah. Letter to Faulk. April 27, 1868. 5 pp.
Cowles, N. M. H. Letter to Faulk. December 22, 1871. 1 p.
Cowles, Warren. Letter to W. A. Burleigh. June 24, 1869. 2 pp.
---- Two letters to Faulk. December 20, 23, 1870. 2 pp.
Crawford, G. T [?]. Letter to Faulk. June 13, 1878. 1 p.
Curriden, Samuel W. Power of attorney for William E. Chandler to Faulk, with abstract of mortgages of Joseph G. Chandler and William E. Chandler signed by J. G. Chandler. October 11, 1886. Typewritten. 7 pp.
Dakota Territory. Legislative Assembly. Council File No. 1. Joint Resolution, recommending the appointment of Faulk as governor. [Broadside. 21 1/2 x 35 1/2 cm.] Certified a true copy by George W. Kingsbury, and on the verso copy of the concurring statement by the judges of the Supreme Court. Signed by the three justices and five other territorial officials. December 7, 1866.
Davis, W. Wallace. Letter to Faulk. November 15, 1866. 2 pp.
DeGray, Charles. Power of attorney to Walter A. Burleigh, to collect money under the Yankton treaty of April 19, 1858. Signed by his mark before J. L. Kelly and Ara Bartlett, with affidavit by Ara Bartlett, September 7, 1868. 3 pp.
DeKay, Drake. Three military passes signed by DeKay, issued to W. A. Burleigh and A. J. Faulk, General Lane and General Pomeroy, and Charles Mason. July 6, 1861. 3 pp.
Del Mar, Alexander. Letter to Faulk. December 5, 1867. Signature only. 2 pp.
Denman, H. B. Letter to Faulk. January 17, 1867. 2 pp.
Dewey, William P. Appointment of Faulk as justice of the peace of Yankton County during absence of George W. Roberts. October 11, 1883. Attested by E. T. White, city clerk, per Blatt. 1 p.
Dorion, Paul. Document assigning to W. A. Burleigh money due under the Yankton treaty of April 19, 1858. Signed by his mark before P. H. Conger and A. C. Guyon, May 19, 1865. Printed form. 1 p.
Dougherty, Maria L. Two letters to Faulk. September 10, 1882, April 22, 1883. 8 pp.
Drew, Joe [?]. Letter to Mark Parmer. September 20, 1879. 4 pp.
Dunlap, W. W. Letter to Faulk. September 23, 1869. 4 pp.
Durley, P. B. Two letters to Faulk. June 27, July 21, 1884. 3 pp.
Ellsworth, Orlando F. Patent, certificate No. 667, for land in Vermillion. September 10, 1870. Signed by President Grant, E. A. Fiske, Assistant Secretary, and J. N. Granger, recorder. Filed for record, May 28, 1872, J. G. Mead, register. Printed form. 40 1/2 x 25 cm.
Emmons, James A. Letter to Faulk. March 29 [n.y.]. 1 p.
Faulk, Jasper H. Power of attorney to A. J. Faulk. September 22, 1842. Witnessed by J. G. Parsons, Leonard Edellen, and Rutherford H. Rountree, clerk of County Court, by Th. J. Purdy, deputy clerk. Filed November 8, 1842. 1 p.
Faulk, John. Two letters to his son, A. J. Faulk. March 21, 1840, June 2, 1853. 4 pp.
---- Commission as justice of the peace, Armstrong Co., Pa., March 4, 1817. Printed form signed by N. B. Boileau, secretary. Filed August 5, 1817, Eben Smith Kelley, recorder. 40 x 34 cm.
Faulk, May. Letter to her grandmother, Mrs. A. J. Faulk. October 7, 1886. 8 pp.
Faulk, Samuel J. Letter to his brother, A. J. Faulk. February 11, 1839. 3 pp.
Faulk, Sarah (Mrs.Thomas B.). Letter to her son, Andrew J. Faulk, 2d. November 12, 1871. 3 pp.
Faulk, Thomas B. 49 letters to his father, Andrew J. Faulk, or his parents. November 26, 1868-June 20, 1887. 118 pp.
---- Five letters to his mother. January 16, 1870-January 11, 1874. 12 pp.
---- Note on John Gilpin. August 24 [n.y.]. 1 p.
---- Petition to President Garfield. Resolution of the Republican County Executive Committee of Armstrong Co., Pa., commending Peter C. Shannon for reappointment as chief justice of Dakota Territory. May 14, 1881. Copy, signed by T. B. Faulk, chairman, A. P. Neale, secretary. 2 pp.
Fenton, Reuben Eaton. Letter to Governor Faulk recommending the appointment of Colonel William S. Rowland as special commissioner to represent the interests of the Northwest at the Paris Exhibition in 1867. September 4, 1866. Signed by the governors of eight states, and attested a true copy by Governor Fenton. September 8, 1866. Parchment. 1 p.
Fletcher, Minnie E. Four letters to Faulk. February 12, 1878-June 17, 1879. 15 pp.
Foster, E. W. Letter to Faulk. April 22, 1892. 1 p.
Fuller, Alpheus G. Letter to Faulk. February 6, 1867. 1 p.
Fuller, Perry. Letter to W. A. Burleigh. September 10, 1868. 1 p.
Fulton, J. Alexander. Letter to Faulk. February 8, 1885. 3 pp.
Gifford, Oscar Sherman. Letter to clerk of the District Court. May 13, 1879. 1 p.
Grafton, Abbie (Mrs. Ben). Letter to Faulk. July 27 [1866?]. 4 pp.
Great European-American Emigration Land Company. Letter to Governor Faulk. February 2, 1869. Signed by J. D. Reymert, secretary. 1 p.
Gregory, J. Shaw. Four letters to Faulk. March 1, 1868- April 4, 1869. 10 pp.
Guyon, Alexander C. Letter to Faulk. November 15, 1868. 1 p.
---- Power of attorney to W. W. Brookings, witnessed by C. F. Picotte, John Treadway. December 26, 1868. Printed form. 1 p.
Hampton, Hugh. Two letters to Faulk. December 20, 1879, [n.d.]. 2 pp.
Hand, George H. Two letters to Faulk. [n.p., n.d.] 2 pp.
---- Letter to Faulk. January 20, 1869. Enclosing pardon and warrant for release of Lewis E. Monger, with 29 signatures. Cheyenne, November 27, 1868. 4 pp.
Hanson, Joseph R. Letter to Faulk. November 14, 1866. 2 p.
Hathaway, T[?]. Letter to Faulk. September 28, 1879. 4 pp.
Hawley, Lucy (Mrs. A. F.). Letter to Faulk. Arpil 16, 1871. 4 pp.
Hayden, Ferdinand Vandiveer. Letter to Faulk. February 22, 1867. 1 p.
Hedges, Charles E. Letter to Faulk. October 23, 1867. 1 p.
---- Contract with Faulk. February 5, 1868. 2 pp.
Hedges, Charles E., and D. T. Letter to Faulk. September 30, 1868. Signed: "J. D. S." 1 p.
Heiner, Robert Graham. Three letters to Faulk. March 4, 1867- September 10, 1874. 9 pp.
Helm, Du Plessis M. Letter to Faulk. August 5, 1867. 1 p.
Herring, C. F. Two letters to Faulk. September 23, 1871, September 9, 1875. Signed: "per A. F. W." 1 p.
Hoffman, Charles W. Letter to Faulk. April 14, 1869. 1 p.
Holley, Frances C. Letter and post card to Faulk. July 20, August 4, 1891. 1 p.
Hooker, C. D. Letter to J. M. Stone. February 24, 1871. Signed: "A." 2 pp.
Hubbard, Dana L. Letter to Faulk. February 12, 1869. With postscript by W. A. Burleigh. 1 p.
Hughes, Alexander. Two letters to Faulk. April 7, 1877, December 28, 1888. 2 pp.
Humphrey, H. A. Nine letters to Faulk. March 21, 1883-March 18, 1895. 18 pp.
Humphrey, S. E. B. (Mrs. H. A.). Two letters to Faulk. May 11, 1884, June 4, 1886. 4 pp.
Hunter, W. Letter to Faulk. June 17, 1886. 1 p.
Jayne, William. Letter to Faulk. December 16, 1866. 1 p.
Johnson, Henry. Four letters to Faulk. September 5, 1853-March 29, 1869. 6 pp.
Jolley, John L. Letter to Faulk. October 18, 1867. 1 p.
Kellogg, N. G. Two letters to Faulk. May 10, 1866, February 7, 1868. 2 pp.
Kelly, James Louden. Three letters to his father-in-law, A. J. Faulk. December 18, 1876-February 24, 1877. 10 pp.
---- Letter to Mark Parmer. September 14, 1879. 3 pp.
---- Affidavit regarding accounts of Dakota Territory, July 23, 1875. Certified by Joel A. Potter, July 26, 1875. 6 pp.
Kelly, Lane Faulk (Mrs. James L.). Letter to her parents. July 4, 1884. 4 pp.
Kelly, R. M. Letter to Faulk. September 30, 1877. 2 pp.
Kidder, Jefferson Parish. Three letters to Faulk. May 7, 1868- December 30, 1882. 3 pp.
Kipp, Louisa. Power of attorney to W. W. Brookings, December 26, 1868. Signed by her mark, witnesses C. F. Picotte and A. C. Guyon. 1 p.
Klotz, E. Letter to Faulk. November 15, 1866. 2 pp.
Kountz, William J. Letter to Faulk. December 16, 1882. 1 p.
LaBaree, John. Three letters to Faulk. April 26- September 11, 1880. 6 pp.
Lamont, S. Colin. Power of attorney to W. W. Brookings. December 15, 1868. Witnessed by B. E. Wood, C. F. Picotte. Printed form 1 p.
Lanphere, Webster Benton. Three letters to Faulk. October 4, 1872- August 30, 1873. 6 pp.
Lewis, Sarah Davis Faulk (Mrs. J. A.). Two letters to her father, A. J. Faulk. March 18, 1867, July 17, 1868. 8 pp.
---- Letter to her mother. April 20, 1868. 4 pp.
Little, Thomas. Letter to Brevet Brigadier General O. D. Greene. March 5, 1869, enclosing a letter to Governor Faulk, March 3, 1869, and sworn statements of Peter Frank, February 7 and March 4, 1869, Henry J. Blunt, February 7, 1869, Frederic Brandt, March 4, 1869, Wakon-ja-kea, March 5, 1869, and Charles Boegehold, March 5, 1869, sustaining the accusations against John B. Gerard. 18 pp.
The letter to General Greene was endorsed by Colonel De Trobriand, forwarded to General Terry, and forwarded by him to Governor Faulk, April 9, 1869.
McCook, Edwin Stanton. Letter to W. A. Burleigh. February 22, 1872. With note on verso from Burleigh to Faulk. 1 p.
McCormick, Richard C. Letter to Faulk. August 15, 1868. 1 p.
McCoy, A. A. Letter to Faulk. June 28, 1887. Signed also by John Bulman. 1 p.
Mann, William L. Letter to Faulk. January 30, 1863. 2 pp.
Maxwell, H. A. Letter to Faulk. November 16, 1869. 2 pp.
Mechling, Frank. Two letters to Faulk. February 26, November 3, 1869. 7 pp.
Meckling, J. S. Letter to J. M. Stone. July 31, 1875. 2 pp.
Merrill, George D. Letter to Faulk. November 20, 1868. 3 pp.
Millard, Ezra. Letter to Faulk. December 11, 1867. 1 p.
Mills, David M. Letter to Faulk. April 11, 1869. 1 p.
Moody, Gideon Curtis. Two letters to Faulk. February 20, 1871, June 20, 1878. 2 pp.
---- Letter to P. C. Shannon. March 27, 1878. 1 p.
---- Letter to the editors of the Press and Dakotan, endorsing Judge Shannon. January 18, 1876. Signed by Moody and 13 others. 2 pp.
Morrison, A. H. Letter to J. M. Stone. January 23, 1878. 1 p.
Morse, A. W. Letter to Faulk. December 16, 1886. 1 p.
Morton, Oliver Perry. Letter to Faulk. November 1, 1866, recommending Luther R. Martin. Signed also by Charles A. Ray and Thomas A. Hendricks. 1 p.
Nagler, Robert. Letter to Faulk. March 4, 1868. Enclosing a recommendation signed by Governor Butler of Nebraska, February 26, 1862. 5 pp.
Ordway, George L. Five letters to Faulk. December 26, 1883-January 9, 1885. 7 pp.
Ordway, Nehemiah G. Two letters to Faulk. November 8, 21, 1882. Signed also by J. C. McVay and George R. Scougal. Copies. 3 pp.